the day before we actually crossed the
border there was a final it's called an
order of battle meeting so George asked
me to be the notetaker in this meeting
George Tennant the director of the CIA
George is at the head of a conference
room table and I'm sitting directly
behind his right shoulder taking the
notes and everybody else is on a TV
screen right and then the general
says if all goes as planned we can be in
teron by August George is sitting there
and then he leans forward and turns off
his microphone and he
says did he say Baghdad or did he say
Teran and I said he said
teron and George says have these people
lost their
minds and then he turns the microphone
back on and just
sits my station Chief in
Pakistan on the strength of the Abu beta
capture was promoted to associate deputy
director for
operations
so he calls me and he says you need a
job I said actually no I just got a job
they put me in charge of Counter
Intelligence for uh Alex station and he
said yeah well they just made the made
the associate deputy director and he
said I want you to come up to the
seventh floor and be an executive
assistant I said oh done
done
so my first day on the job was the
following Monday and I go in and I said
okay so what are we doing and he says I
actually can't tell you you have to go
to this room on the sixth floor and
there are some secrecy agreements for
you to sign and then we'll tell you what
we're
doing and I said okay so I went to the
sixth floor and knocked on the door and
I knew the guy who told me to come in
and I said oh hey what are you what are
you doing he said so you're the new
executive assistant wow you've made a a
heck of a a heck of a path for yourself
I said yeah I got lucky Pakistan was
totally
positive um I said what are we doing and
he said well why don't you sign these
first and then I'll explain everything
so there were six of them and I signed
six secrecy agreements saying I'll never
ever reveal what I'm about to learn
unless it's Declassified which it has
been and so I sign I go okay what's up
and he goes well now this is this is May
of
2002 2002 he goes well next year in
February we're going to invade Iraq
we're going to overthrow Saddam Hussein
and we're going to open the largest Air
Force Base in the world so that we can
move all of our air assets out of Saudi
Arabia and deprive Osama Bin Laden of
the ability to say that we're polluting
the land of the two holy
mosques I was
dumbfounded and all I could even blurt
out was but we haven't caught Bin Laden
yet and he said buddy the decision's
been made and the battle lines have been
drawn he said he said CIA is opposed to
this state is opposed to this and The
Joint Chiefs are
opposed but the ones that are for it are
ovp the office of the vice president OSD
the office of the Secretary of Defense
and the National Security
Council and I said so the decision's
been made he said the decision's been
made yeah so I walked back
downstairs and the boss
says so you're readed in and I said are
they out of their minds and he said yes
they
are but we're not a policy agency we're
a support agency and if they tell us to
invade Iraq and overthrow Saddam Hussein
that's what we're going to do and so
that's what we worked on until we
invaded Iraq and overthrew Saddam
Hussein so tenant was the director at
this time right yes and uh didn't you I
don't know if it was the same day or not
but walk by his office and see him doing
a little art project in there oh it
wasn't tenant okay I went up to the uh
it was the chief of something called the
Iraq operations
group um I had to pick up a briefing
book uh there was a principal's meeting
a the principal meeting it's it's a
policy meeting chaired by the Vice
President um and it has the Secretary of
Defense Secretary of State National
Security
adviser um CIA director NSA director and
chairman and vice chairman of the Joint
Chiefs of
Staff so I went to pick up the
book and
uh and the chief of the Iraq operations
group he's sitting there with a piece of
paper and he's got these
Crayola um what do you call them the
Crayons no not the crayons but the magic
markers I go whatat are you doing he
says oh I'm designing the new Iraqi flag
I said don't you think the Iraqis should
design the new Iraqi flag he goes I
don't know I thought I'd do it and I
said you're using the colors of the
Israeli
flag like this is what happens when they
put a Mexican guy in charge of the Iraq
operations group I said buddy the Iraqi
flag is is the colors that it is for a
reason right you got to have green
because it represents Islam you have to
have red because it represents the
ethnic minorities right you got to have
the three stars because that represents
uh the the sunnis the Shia and the
Kurds you can't just take the Israeli
flag and change it around a little bit
so thank God nothing ever came of that
but they were
serious it it got worse than that that
was minor it got way worse than that how
so people just getting too big for their
Bridges well the day before the day
before we actually crossed the border um
there was a final it's called an order
of battle meeting I always hated the
order of battle meetings because I'm not
a military analyst and I just don't care
where elements of the Fifth Army Corps
are in comparison to the third infantry
division I don't
care right let the generals figure that
out I trust in their judgment you don't
have to tell me that the the 23rd
Infantry mounted division is I I don't
care so George asked me to be the
notetaker in this meeting George Tennant
the director of the CIA asked me to to
be the
notetaker and
um the meeting was chaired by the Vice
President so it was Cheney and his guys
like scooter Libby and a couple of other
people coni rice Colin Powell um the
chairman and vice chairman of the joint
Chiefs Don
Rumsfeld ki's Deputy um Hadley Steve
Hadley Steve Hadley I couldn't remember
his first name he was there and then
General I forget his name he was
commander of centcom at the time he had
replaced uh you know Schwarz and [__]
and all these other people that had come
after Schwarz General was it Taylor
Maybe Taylor can't remember anymore so
Cheney starts the meeting General why
don't you give us the order of battle
I'm
like so I'm
sitting George is at George is at the
head of a conference room table and
everybody else is on a TV screen right
and George's microphone is right in
front of him and he's just sitting there
like this and I'm sitting directly
behind his right shoulder taking the
notes so we're sitting there and they're
like the Fifth Army Corps is in this
position and the 23rd infantry is here
and they're going to move north and this
one's going to move west and this one's
going to come South and the blah blah
blah blah blah and I'm writing it all
down and then the general
says if all goes as planned we can be in
teron by August George is sitting there
and then he leans forward and turns off
off his microphone and he
says did he say Baghdad or did he say
teron and I said he said
teron and George says have these people
lost their
minds and then he turns the microphone
back on and just
sits so I'm taking all the
notes and one of these idiots from the
NSC says when we cross the border
they're going to throw flowers at us and
I wrote it
down the meeting ends I go back to the
deputy director's office he said how'd
the meeting go and I said did you know
we were going to invade Iran and he goes
ooh are they still talking about
that and I go yeah they said we could be
in Iran by by August and he goes
listen we're not invading
Iran we're probably not even going to be
successful in
Iraq but these guys don't know anything
about the Middle East
nothing we're not going invade Iran they
talk about it like they they think they
know what they're talking about and they
don't know
anything I go okay I I hope you're right
and sure enough we got bogged down in
Iraq never never went anywhere near
Iran what's up guys thank you so much
for taking the time to watch interview
um as you could probably tell this is a
brand new channel so if you got anything
out of this at all please like the video
leave me a comment tell me what you
thought tell me who you'd like to see on
the show um I see every like I read
every comment and I appreciate all of it
especially in the beginning because as
you know that kind of support goes a
long way on these platforms so most
importantly I have some awesome guests
coming up in the future for interviews
um so please subscribe to the channel so
you don't miss any of them but again
thank you for your time appreciate the
support and hope to see you again soon